Jim Paul Punay

09335139791 | punayjimpaul@gmail.com

Summary

A responsible, approachable, and confident person, highly self-motivated, who works hard to achieve the best in every situation. Versatile individual with experience in collecting, transforming, and organizing data for analysis to help make informed decision. Proficient of platforms for effective data analysis, including SQL, spreadsheets, Tableau, R and Python. Have also worked with programming languages such as C++ and Java. Strong communication, organizational, and analytical skills is my expertise and finds reward in gaining responsibility, goals, and objectives. A six-sigma green belt holder.

Key Competencies

- С
- C++
- Java
- PostgreSQL
- Tableau
- Jira and Confluence
- Data Governance

- Glassbox
- Threading
- R
- Data Analytics
- · Machine Learning
- RDBMS
- Quality Control

Professional Experience



Data Analyst, Operational Research & Reporting

Qualfon

Jun 2023 - Present (9 months)

- Generated reports by gathering data and presenting it in a manner that is intuitive and professional. Used reporting tools to monitor key performance metrics regarding website and customer behavior, as well as backend/front end errors.
- Conducted research on issues encountered by customers and gather findings to produce comprehensive and insightful results.
- Effectively communicated research findings in a clear and concise manner that is easily understood by business units, IT, and executives alike
- Provided full support during production releases.
- Properly documented issues and findings regarding all aspects of the job
- Trained and mentor junior members of the team to ensure quality and efficiency of work performance is minimally affected.
- Used work collaboration tools to effectively manage tasks and assign items accordingly.

Data Research Analyst

With Intelligence

Jun 2022 - Jun 2023 (1 year 1 month)

- Took ownership of projects from a global universe of investors
- Collected data from various sources from clients such as databases and other data systems, that could help investors and clients.
- Tracked and Monitored Financial Markets
- Updates Key Financial Data.
- Ensured all financial data are accurate and up to date.
- Maintained a high level of quality across all profile builds.
- · Developed recommendation based on the data and insights to support portfolio managers in their investment strategies.
- Liaised with contacts primarily through outbound emails and phone calls (internationally)



Business Associate

Accenture

Oct 2019 - May 2020 (8 months)

- Identified inefficiencies in operations and developing solutions.
- Drawn insights that can inform business decisions.
- Optimized existing processes and developed new process to improve operational efficiency, reduce cost, and enhance customer experience.
- Identified bottlenecks and propose solutions to streamline processes.
- Provided support for marketing campaigns, product launches, or brand management activities.
- Supported in developing policies and training programs to minimize organizational risk.

Education



University of Cebu

Computer Software Servicing 2017 - 2019

Saint Paul College Foundation Inc.

High School Jun 2014 - 2017

Licenses & Certifications



Google Data Analytics - Google

VTC77NVVN9W3



Lean Six Sigma Green Belt - KEISEN Consultores PH-

QC16SGB23084403